DITERIMA

27 DEC 2011

Compressed



INTRODUCTION

Name : PROFESSOR Ir. Dr. MOHD JAILANI BIN MOHD NOR

Identification card no. : 620817-10-6297 (6884313)

: 17th August, 1962 / Bangi, Selangor Date/Place of Birth

: Professor / Director **Current Post**

Address : IHE Excellence Planning Division

> Department of Higher Education Ministry of Higher Education Level 6, Block E1, Precint E

62505 Putrajaya

: 03 - 88706961 (office) Telephone No

012-2097571 (mobile)

: jai@mohe.gov.my E-mail

FIELD OF EXPERTISE

Mechanical Engineering: Acoustics and Vibration;

Machine Condition Monitoring;

5 (9th August 2011) H-Index:

Citations: 195

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Sheffield Hallam University, U.K.	Ph. D.	1993 - 1996
Oklahoma State University, USA	Msc. Mech. Eng.	1986 - 1988
Technical Teaching College, K. Lumpur.	Cert. of Education	1985
Oklahoma State University, USA	B. Sc. Mech. Eng.	1980 - 1984
Kajang High School	M.C.E	1978 - 1979
Sek. Men. Engku Hussain, Semenyih	L.C.E.	1975 - 1977

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

P. Eng., Board of Engineers Malaysia	13114
Member, Board of Engineers Malaysia	12423A
Member, International Institute of Acoustics & Vibration (IIAV)	955
Member, Malaysian Society for Non-Destructive Testing	102/90
	00.0554

SS 0551 I 00207 Registered Consultant, Department of Environment, Malaysia

President, Protem Committee, Society for Vibration and

Acoustics Malaysia (SVAM).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Deputy Vice Universiti Teknikal Melaka (UTeM) 1st January 2011

Chancellor

Director: **Excellence Planning Division IHE** 1st January 2009 -

Department of Higher Education, 31st Dec 2011.

Ministry of Higher Education Malaysia.

Board of Director: UMS-Link Sdn Bhd, Universiti Malaysia Sabah 2009 - present

(UMS).

Board of Director: K-UTech Sdn Bhd., UTHM 2010 - present Universiti Tun Hussein Onn Board of Director: 2009 - present Malaysia

(UTHM)

Deputy Director: Centre For Research and Innovation 1st March 2007 -

Management, UKM Dec 2008

present

Professor: Department of Mechanical and Materials 25th August 2005 -

Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, UKM

Faculty of Engineering & Built Environement, Deputy Dean: 1st June 2003 -(Academic) UKM 31st March 2007.

Head of Department: Department of Mechanical and Materials

1st April 1999 -Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, UKM May 2003 2nd June 1988

Lecturer: Department of Mechanical and Materials Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, UKM

AWARDS (SELECTED)

Special Quality Award i. 11th October 2002

Best Lab Management Award (Group Category)

Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia 10th Quality Award Ceremony

Excellent Service Award 23rd October 2003 ii.

Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia 11th Quality Award Ceremony

Gold medal, Seoul International Invention Fair 2004, SIIF iii. 10 - 14th December

2004. Coex. Seoul. Korea. 2004

Product: *Driver's Drowsiness Detection and Interactive* Warning System

Bronze medal, 33rd International Exhibition of Inventions, 6 - 10th April 2005. iv.

Geneva, Switzerland.

Product: Intelligent Heart Monitoring System

Special Quality Award 28th November 2005 v.

Quality Culture Award (Academic Staff)

Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia

13th Quality Award Ceremony

Silver medal, Innovative Acoustic Absortion Panel Design Using vi. 12th August 2007

Natural Fibre, International Exposition of Research and

Inventions of Institution of Higher Learning 2007, PECIPTA07, K. Lumpur.

Gold medal, Innovative Acoustic Absorption Panel Design Using vii.

3rd November 2007. Natural Fibre, Internationale Fachmesse >> Ideen-Erfindunen-

Neuheiten<<, Nurnberg, Germany.

TEACHING

KM 2052 Applied Mechanics II KM 2062 Engineering Control I KM2343 Dynamics KF2223 Ethics: Technology and Civilisation	KM 2082 Strength of Materials KM 2222 Machine Design KM2933 Machine Component Design KM2443 Strength of Materials
KM 3072 Applied Mechanics III KM 3212 Complex Engineering Design KM 3232 Advanced Laboratory	KM4342 Advanced Dynamics KM4343 Mechanical Vibrations KM4353 Acoustics
LS6403 Environmental Pollution Control	KJ6043 Advanced Instrumentation

STUDENT SUPERVISION

Undergraduate:	Masters Degree	PhD Students
48 Undergraduate student projects.	13 Masters students supervised and completed.	9 PhD students supervised and completed.

PUBLICATIONS

Books: Written and edited more than fifteen (15) books. **Journals:** Published more than Sixty (60) journal papers.

Keynote and Invited Papers: Presented more than eighteen (18) keynote and invited

papers.

Conferences: Published and presented about one hundred and ninety (190)

conference papers.

Technical Reports Articles in Popular Publications:

Written more than twenty (20) technical reports and articles in popular publications.

INTELLECTUAL PROPERTIES

Trade Mark Registration:

- 1. Interactive online driver drowsiness detection and Early Warning System (**IDES**[™]) Trademark Registration applied for Class 16 & Class 42.
- 2. Automotive Simulator for Drivers behaviour anthropotechnic Study (ASIS™) Trademark Registration applied for Class 16 & Class 42.
- 3. Intelligent Heart Condition Monitoring System (**i-Heartz**™) Trademark Registration applied for Class 16 & Class 42.

CONSULTANCIES

Conducted more than thirty (30) consultancy projects in sound and vibration field for industrial clients including Tenaga Nasional Berhad (TNB), Independent Power Provider (IPP), Putrajaya Holdings (PJH), Keretapi Tanah Melayu (KTM), Pusat Tenaga Malaysia (PTM), and Petroleum Nasional Berhad (Petronas).

SELECTED R&D PROJECTS

1. Title : Development and Production of Indigeneous Vibro-Acoustic Control

Materials and Systems

Sponsor : IRPA 09-02-02-0044 (**RM457,000.00**)

Role : Project Leader

Duration: 1999 - December 2002

2. Title : Development of a Machine Faults Diagnostics System Using Air Borne

Ultrasonic Signals

Sponsor : IRPA 09-02-02-0056 (RM253,000.00)

Role : Project Leader

Duration: 1999 - December 2002

:

3. Title : Development of Noise Absorption Structural Panels Using Coir

Fibre/TPNR Composites

Sponsor : IRPA 09-02-02-0101(**RM123,002.00**)

Rule : Project Leader

Duration: 2000 - February 2003

4. Title : Development of MEMS Instrumentation and Diagnostic Systems for

Automotive Applications

Sponsor : IRPA 03-02-02-0016-SR0003/07-02(RM3,885,720.00)

Role : Project Leader

Status : Completed June 2007.

5. Title : Penyelidikan Mengenai Pendidikan Berasaskan Hasil (PBH) di Fakulti

Kejuruteraan, UKM

Sponsor : KK005/2005 (**RM27,716.00**)

Role : Project Leader

Status : Completed June 2007.

6. Title : *Vibro-Acoustics Modeling, Prediction and Development of Control*

Systems for Road Transport

Sponsor : 03-01-02-SF0081(**RM55,998.00**)

Role : Project Leader Status : Completed 2010.

7. Title : Development of Active Sound Absorption Panel Using Agro-Based

Organic Fibre

Sponsor : 03-01-02-SF393 (**RM129,000.00**)

Role : Project Leader Status : Completed 2010

PRE-COMMERCIALISATION PROJECT

1. Title: Development of Automotive Driving Simulator

Sponsor: CRDF 3 (RM500,000.00)
Role: Principle Technical Investigator

Industry Partner: SVI Sdn Bhd

Duration: January 2010 - December 2011.